ifrc.org 2019-09-07

# Disclaimer - International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies

All information contained in this web site is Copyright  
© The International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies. All rights reserved.

  * To use text information from this web site, please obtain prior permission from the [IFRC](https://www.ifrc.org/en/Contact-us/?id=57576).
  * To use photographs from this web site, please contact our [audiovisual department](mailto:av@ifrc.org).
  * Please note that many of our operations documents are in PDF format, for which you need Acrobat Reader to view. This can be downloaded free from [Adobe](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep.html).
  * If you have any questions about this web site, or if you find any errors, please [notify us](https://www.ifrc.org/en/Contact-us/?id=21272).
  * [Important information about fraudulent web sites and e-mails](https://www.ifrc.org/en/warning/?id=46922).
  * The Federation’s Secretariat is a member of [AlertNet – humanitarian aid and disaster news](http://www.alertnet.org/).

## Privacy policy

This web site is operated by the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies (“the Federation”). The users of this web site are subject to the following privacy policy. This policy does not apply to pages hosted by other organizations, including National Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies and the International Committee of the Red Cross, which have their own privacy policies. The Federation takes your privacy and the security of your personal information –meaning any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual –  seriously. Please take a moment to read this privacy policy and learn about the Federation’s general privacy and information security principles. 

The Federation is the world’s largest international humanitarian network, reaching 150 million people, with 190 member Red Cross and Red Crescent National Societies and the work of over 17 million volunteers. The IFRC together with the Red Cross and Red Crescent National Societies and the International Committee of the Red Cross form the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement. As part of the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement, our work is guided by seven fundamental principles; humanity, impartiality, neutrality, independence, voluntary service, unity and universality. Together, we act before, during and after disasters and health emergencies to meet the needs and improve the lives of vulnerable people. We do so without discrimination as to nationality, race, religious beliefs, class or political opinions. 

**(A) Terms of Use**

The content placed on this web site is within the sole discretion of the Federation. The Federation retains the right to modify any aspect of this web site, including but not limited to the terms of use, copyright policy and privacy policy.

All users of this web site agree to abide by the policies contained herein. No one may use this web site in a manner that is contrary to the Fundamental Principles of the Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement ([http://www.ifrc.org/who-we-are/vision-and-mission/the-seven-fundamental-principles/](http://www.ifrc.org/who-we-are/vision-and-mission/the-seven-fundamental-principles/)).

**(B) Use of personal information; Choice/Opt Out**

We use your personal information for processing your donations. We can also send you information and materials that we believe may be of interest to you. If you wish to receive information from us and you have not previously given us your consent to contact you, please let us know by contacting us at [privacy.queries@ifrc.org](mailto:privacy.queries@ifrc.org). At any point if you no longer wish to receive any communications from us, please let us know by contacting us at the same address.

As a general rule, the Federation will not disclose any information identifying you personally, except with your permission or where required by law. Information you provide to the Federation will not be sold to third parties or used in a manner inconsistent with the aims of the web site. Information may be shared with the Federation membership or other components of the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement, to further facilitate humanitarian assistance. Some information identifying donors to the Federation is forwarded to third parties for purely technical and administrative processing. These parties are not authorized to distribute, sell or rent user information.

**(C) Non-personal information (cookies)**

Cookies are text files that contain small amounts of information that we may store on your device when you use our site. Cookies enable us to monitor site traffic and estimate our audience size and usage pattern as well as allowing us to store information about your preferences to allow us to customise our site according to those preferences. They also help us to improve our site and deliver a more personalised service. We use the following types of cookies in connection with our site:

Strictly Necessary: These cookies enable our site to function correctly and deliver the services and products visitors have requested. These cookies do not gather information about the visitors that could be used for marketing or remembering sites that visitors have visited on the internet.

Performance and Functionality: These cookies do things like remember a visitor’s preferred language, understand their preferences and associates users to any forms visitor’s submit to use to enable pre-completion of subsequent forms. 

Analytical: These cookies help us analyse how our site is used, such as allowing us to compile reports on website activity and providing us other services relating to website activity and internet usage. 

User Authentication: These social media cookies allow visitors to login to share and promote their activities via social media. 

Our site will issue cookies to your device when you log on to the site. Cookies may either be permanent (i.e., remaining on your device until you delete them) or temporary (i.e. remaining only until you close your browser). Most browsers permit you to reject or delete cookies.

If you do choose to block cookies, you may not be able to use certain features on our site and/or may be required to re-enter information more frequently to use certain services on the site.  If you would like to know more about cookies, including Flash cookies, the following website provides useful information www.youronlinechoices.eu.

**(D) Level of security and disclaimer**

The Federation uses secure systems and implements appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal information and protect it against unauthorised or unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction, or damage. While we take reasonable measures to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted on our site. You submit your personal information to us at your risk. 

In addition, our policy is to only permit authorised personnel with a legitimate business purpose to access your personal information submitted to our site.  Where your personal information is shared with third parties of the Federation, we will take reasonable measures to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. These steps may include requiring those companies to implement no less than equivalent security measures than those offered by the Federation under this privacy policy.

You should be aware that information sent to us using site may not be secure in transmission. Please be aware of this when sending any communications.  We cannot (and do not) guarantee absolute security. 

Notification of any change to this privacy policy will be posted on this web site. If you have any questions regarding this policy, please contact the Federation.

**(E) Access to Your Data** ** **

Where permitted by law, you may request access to personal information we hold about you. An access request may be subject to a small fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. Should you wish to access the information held about you, please let us know by contacting: [privacy.queries@ifrc.org](mailto:privacy.queries@ifrc.org). We will process that request in line with any local laws and our policies and procedures in place for dealing with such requests. There may however, be circumstances where we are unable to provide access to your personal information. We may deny or restrict access for legally permissible reasons, such as where it cannot be disclosed for legal, security or other commercial proprietary reasons. Where appropriate, we will advise you of any reason for denying or restricting an access request.

Further, if your personal information changes or if you have any queries about how we use your information, please let us know by contacting us as at the same address.

**(F) Privileges and Immunities**

Nothing in or relating to this privacy policy or this site shall be deemed a waiver of any of the privileges and immunities of the Federation.
